<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A salutation of true love to all faithful friends, brethren and sisters in the fellowship of the blessed truth with an addition of tender love to all younger convinced friends in and about London &amp;c. : also a few words of advice to the children of believing and faithful parents.</title>
            <author>Fisher, A. (Abigail)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1690</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 27 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 11 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A41347</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing F986</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R37815</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">17022013</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 17022013</idno>
            <idno type="VID">105837</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A41347)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 105837)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1615:26)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A salutation of true love to all faithful friends, brethren and sisters in the fellowship of the blessed truth with an addition of tender love to all younger convinced friends in and about London &amp;c. : also a few words of advice to the children of believing and faithful parents.</title>
                  <author>Fisher, A. (Abigail)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[4], 16 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Thomas Northcott ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1690.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed: Abigal Fisher.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: print show-through.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Society of Friends --  Pastoral letters and charges.</term>
               <term>Christian life --  Quaker authors.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:105837:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A SALUTATION OF TRUE LOVE TO ALL Faithful Friends, Brethren and Siſters, IN THE <hi>Fellowſhip of the Bleſſed Truth.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>WITH An Addition of Tender Love to all younger convinced Friends, in and about <hi>London,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>ALSO A Few words of Advice to the Children of Believing and Faithful Parents.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Thomas Northcott,</hi> in <hi>George-Yard,</hi> in <hi>Lumbard-ſtreet,</hi> 1690.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:105837:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:105837:2"/>
            <head>TO THE READER.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>Dear Friends,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>REmembring the good Houſholder that brought forth out of his Treaſury, Things both New and Old; I am made willing to Communicate this following Salutation, which was written ſome Time ſince, chiefly to my Elder Faithful Brethren and Siſters: But meeting with various Exerciſes, in which Time the Enemy was not wanting to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courage me, I laid it by. But now feel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Renewings of the Love of God towards you, and a freſh Stream of Love and Life from the ſame Fountain, run<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in my Soul, and opening my Heart
<pb facs="tcp:105837:3"/> towards my Younger Convinced Friends, I now after this Salutation to you, commit what follows to their ſerious Reading and Conſideration; who am, and trust in God, ſhall Remain in true Love, your Friend, and their Fellow-Traveller, till I may arrive at my deſired Reſt, which is to lay down my Head in Peace with the Lord.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>A. F.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:105837:3"/>
            <head>A SALUTATION OF TRUE LOVE</head>
            <p>TO you my Dear and Well-beloved Friends, Faithful Brethren and Siſters, whom my Soul feels a Uniting to, in the Spirit of the Living God, which hath quickned and made you a living People, who once were Dead as well as others; but through the Riches of the Love of God in the Revelation of his Son Chriſt Jeſus, are made alive to Praiſe him; whoſe gather<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Arm hath been made bare for our Salvation, and Preſervation from under Satan's Thraldom, in which we were held by his dark Power, which did bear Rule, and Captivate our Minds, inſomuch, that many were Slaves, till the Lord was pleaſed to reach forth the Hand of his Divine Love, and make known the Right Arm of his Heavenly Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er to gather us, who with his Shepherds Crook did reach unto us, and found us out; by which, he hath brought many near unto himſelf, and they are his Elect, and Precious in his Sight, to whom he
<pb facs="tcp:105837:4"/> hath and will Reveal his bleſſed Mind and Will; and for whom, he hath, and will yet ariſe to plead with all that ſhall Combine againſt him, or thoſe whom he hath called for a Purpoſe of his own Glory, by whom he hath, and doth yet intend through the work of his Spirit, to ſhew forth his excellent Name, which is as Precious Ointment to them, who through the Vertue thereof, have ſmelt the good Savour which many ſhall yet greatly deſire: For the Lord that hath begun a <hi>Work of Reformation,</hi> will yet go on to a further perfecting the ſame in this our Age; and many have been the Viſitations of the Long-ſuffering God, who hath, and will yet come in, and with the Sanctified, to Judge and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demn the Unſanctified, and eſpecially thoſe that have profeſſed his worthy Name, but have lived in that which hath diſhonoured, and cauſed it to be Evil ſpoken of by thoſe who know it not; but la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentable is their Caſe, except they Repent and Turn to the Lord with their whole Hearts, that have been Convinced of the Truth, and in ſome Meaſure know the working of that Power, which is alone ſufficient to Convert and work a Change, as it is yielded to, through the Lively Operation thereof, which works by Love in the Hearts of all that ſincerely deſire to be Tranſlated from Death to Life, that they may be as Living Monu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of the Mercies of God, which to the Praiſe of his Name be it ſpoken, many are.</p>
            <p>And theſe are they to whom the Lord hath, and is ſpreading his Table with many Delicates, and they know the Manſion-houſe where their Bread is ſure, and their Water never fails; Come Eat with me this day my well beloved, and drink of the Wine of
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:105837:4"/> the Kingdom, for it is new and newly poured forth, through the Flagons of God's Love to you who are indwellers where his mercy Seat you have beheld, and where you can approach, before the Throne of his heavenly Grace, and where his honourable Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence you do behold when the Light of his Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenance is lifted up upon you: O then, his Love you feel as a ſtrong Cord which draws you to love him again, and you are the eſpouſed to Chriſt, who can ſay, <hi>in truth he is my Beloved, and I am his;</hi> you feel his bleſſing to light upon you, as the Dew which cauſes you to grow, and you are as the Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den of God which he delights to dreſs and prune, and much Labour hath the Lord beſtowed on you, whoſe love is felt at this time as the ſmall Rain deſcending on every Plant, that his Right hand hath planted, that they may grow in their Seaſon as the Summer Fruits which are beautiful to behold. Friends, my Soul is greatly affected with what the Lord hath done<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and is doing for a People that are willing to be the Workmanſhip of his hands, whoſe ſincere Cry is to the Lord, not only to know his Will which is the Sanctification of his People, but alſo to know the word of his Power, which is as a Hammer and as a fire to beat down and burn up all the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buſtible matter; and you are they that have and are coming thus to know the Travel of your Souls through an holy Subjection to the Mind and Will of God, that he will and doth ſtand by, and ſecretly make way for through all outward and inward Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition; but to ſuch who may not be ſo nearly ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thered, this Exhortation ſprings from the Root of true Love; Retire to the Lord and draw near to him who hath promiſed he will draw near to you;
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:105837:5"/> and Chriſt ſaid, <hi>They that come unto me I will in no ways caſt off;</hi> Bleſſed be the Lord there are many witneſſes, therefore let all be encouraged, he is faithful who hath promiſed; many can ſeal to the Teſtimony whom he hath made partakers of the Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefit thereof, and they have reapt great Advantage by coming unto him; yea when they were wearied and heavy laden with divers ſins, then was his hand ſtretched out to undo the heavy Burthen, and that was a ſign of Love, the remembrance of which bows my Soul before the great God, whoſe Love I feel, and the large extending thereof, reaching to all, and many ſhall be viſited who have not yet felt God's quickning Power, to raiſe their Souls from that Sleep of Death, which Satan hath lull'd them into through harkning unto him, and diſobeying the Command of the great God; but my Friends, I know the dealing of the Lord to you, who are a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wakened and raiſed from Death to Life is as a ſtrong Obligation on your Spirits to walk in the Light of the Lord, where the Morning of God's Day was known to dawn, and the Sun to riſe, that hath ſhined unto the Noon<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> day, by which your hearts have been warmed, and your Spirits ſweetly com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forted, in the ſenſe of which my Soul doth bleſs the Lord, that he hath opened mine Eyes to behold the appearance of this day, in which the glorious Splen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dour and Beams of the Sun of Righteouſneſs hath ſo greatly ſhined, and ſhall yet to many who yet ſet under the Region and ſhadow of Death; notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding the ſecret and open workings of the Enemy of man's Soul, whoſe work is to darken the Mind, and bring a Cloud as a Veil over the Underſtandings of People, that they may not ſee the Light of the
<pb facs="tcp:105837:5"/> glorious Goſpel, that hath and ſhall ſhine through them, who faithfully walk in the Light of this everlaſting day in which the Sun ſhall never ſet; for as the Lord hath been at work, ſo he will work, and none ſhall be able to hinder his determined Will, which is to exalt his Son; who ſaid of himſelf, <hi>I am the Way, the Truth, the Life and the Light;</hi> he alſo ſaid, <hi>he that believeth in me ſhall not abide in dark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, but ſhall have the Light of Life;</hi> and you are they that do witneſs the Truth of that ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, whom the Lord hath made partaker of ſuch like precious Faith, which he hath beſtowed upon you, and it is not in vain muſt my Soul with yours acknowledge being made a partaker in ſome degree of the ſaving Vertue that is in it, to the Praiſe of the Lord's worthy Name, be it ſpoken, who hath beſtowed it on us, for my heart is filled, and with the abounding thereof doth my Cup overflow, and run as a Salutation to you my well beloved Friends, faithful Brethren and Siſters, in that relation which the Spirit of God hath brought us into through the indwelling Power thereof; even all you that were born of that Royal Seed which is the Off ſpring of <hi>David,</hi> to you the Root of <hi>Jeſſe</hi> is ſprung up in this our day: High praiſes to the Honourable worthy Name of the great God, I know is given by all you who do know the branches of it overſpreading the Earth in your hearts; you are of that Number of whom it was ſpoken, <hi>they that touch the Elect, touch the Apple of God's Eye,</hi> what can be nearer or ſooner felt? O the Love of God as the Bowels of a tender Father, you have known to ſuccour and relieve, to ſave and deliver; he is the ſame this day as ever, and changes not:
<pb facs="tcp:105837:6"/> I know you have had large Experience, even you that have walked the heavenly Progreſs, and run in the Race with Patience which was ſet before you, and are coming towards an End of your Travels, which hath been through many Difficul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, for many Troubles have been the Portion of of the Righteous; may I not ſay as on your behalf, whom the Lord did call in the breaking forth of this glorious Day, the Light of which now ſhines in the hearts of many, to whom you have been publiſhers to proclaim the ſound of the Everlaſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Goſpel, to which the Ears of many have been opened, and their hearts ready to receive the glad Tidings of Peace, for which my Soul is greatly ingaged to bleſs the Lord, that I was one of that Number to which the ſound hath reached: There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore dear Friends for a farther Confirmation, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieving you have had many, that your faithful La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours and Travels in the Work of the Goſpel of our Lord and Saviour Jeſus Chriſt, hath not been in vain; for I am obliged to acknowledge to the benefit, that I with many more whom I know, have with me been made partakers of the ſame con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolating, refreſhing, ſtrengthening Vertue which the Lord hath through you communicated unto us, who as good Stewards of the manifold Grace of God have diſtributed to the poor in Spirit; who through believing and receiving the Grace of God are made rich in Faith, and Heirs of that King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom that ſhall never have an End: O the Joy of God's Salvation, the Comfort and Conſolation you know who have travelled through, and are gone before by the Aſſiſtance of the heavenly Power, and bleſſed Spirit of the living God, which
<pb facs="tcp:105837:6"/> is one in all the faithful, who truly come to know their Minds and Wills rightly ſubjected to it, and that come to be led and guided by it; ſuch know the Efficacy and Vertue of it, to lead and guide them into Truth, and from all Untruth, and ſuch are they that adorn the Goſpel, and theſe alone are Preachers of Truth and Righteouſneſs, who are taught and learned of him, who never guile was found in his Mouth. O the Righteous holy Princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple of Life, what a Beauty doth mine Eyes behold in it, how comely are you who have kept your firſt Love to it, and have not made ſhipwrack of Faith, but have this day the Anſwer of a good Conſcience towards God and all Men! Friends, the ſenſe of your everlaſting Joy and endleſs Felicity, when the Lord ſhall remove you out of theſe earthly Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bernacles and Houſes of Clay, begets a fervent de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire in me, that we who are as the younger begot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten, but brought forth by the ſame Arm and mighty Power of God, and have hitherto been brought up, and nouriſhed by the ſame Milk of the Word, may grow thereby from ſtrength to ſtrength, till we come to the Stature and fulneſs of a Man in Chriſt, and that the hindermoſt of the Flock may come up, and follow in the Foot-ſteps of you that are gone before in that ſtraight and narrow Way which leads to Life, that hereby we may come to be enriched with the ſame heavenly Treaſure; and though younger begotten yet as right Heirs may come to have a part and ſhare in that Joy, which is unſpeakable, and full of Glory: Now my ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable eſteemed Fathers, and Elders, faithful Brethren and Siſters in that Life, that ſhall out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>live Death, and the Power of it; and in true Love
<pb facs="tcp:105837:7"/> do I ſalute you all whom the Lord hath called, and made choice of to promote Truth, and Righteouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs in the Earth; though many are your Gain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſayers, the Truth is that which the Lord will ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretly make way for through all Oppoſition: Bleſſed and magnified over and through all be his Almighty Power, which is at work this day for the furthe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance of it; for which Cauſe the faithful have great Cauſe to be incouraged to go on, in the ſtrength of the Lord, who will turn and overturn till he come to Reign, whoſe Right it is, in the Hearts of the Children of Men,</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>From a younger Siſter, but one that deſires to be a faithful Follower of the Flock of God, A. F.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="text">
            <head>A Viſitation of Tender Love, as I felt it Running in a freſh Stream of Life to you my Friends, who are younger convinced in and about <hi>London.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>DEar Friends, Brethren and Siſters, whom I love in the Lord; and deſire well for, as for my own Soul, that you may all grow in Grace, and in the Knowledge of God; whom to rightly know is Life Eternal; the Teſtimony of which, hath been often ſounded in your Ears through many worthy Antients, whom the Lord by his immediate Power hath fitted for the Publiſhing his Truth, and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forming you of the bleſſed Way of Life and Salva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:105837:7"/> in this our Age: Bleſſed be his Name, his Fame hath ſpread, and ſhall to the Ends of the Earth; He is the ſame God this Day, as ever, his Power is not leſſened, neither is his Arm ſhortned, but his Voice is ſtill uttered, and his Call is, <hi>Come look unto me all ye Ends of the Earth, and be ye ſaved, who ſaves his People from Sin, that they may be Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers of Righteouſneſs;</hi> He ſaith, <hi>I am God, and there is no other;</hi> He is a jealous God, and jealous of his Glory; therefore ſee to it all you who have heard his Call, which I doubt not but many muſt acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge too; therefore this is with me in the Love of God, to you who have heard, but not yet obeyed the Call of the Lord, which is, <hi>Come and be ſaved;</hi> a worthy Call indeed, and worthy of all Accep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation for your Encouragement, that thereby you may come to forſake and deny thoſe things which the Call hath been to you, to come out of, or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>part from either, immediately, by his Spirit in your Hearts, or Inſtrumentally, through any faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Servant, by the Conducts of it; for his Call hath gone long forth, and his Alarming Trumpet hath been long ſounded, and is this Day; Ariſe thou that ſleepeſt, and come to Judgment; for <hi>SION</hi> muſt be Redeemed through Judgment, and all her Converts, with and by that Righteous Principle of Light and Life, by and through which, the Spirit of God's Love and Free Grace hath been, and yet is ſo largely Extended to and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt you, that now you may not only hear, but believe and obey the Goſpel of our Lord, and come to know him to be your Saviour, and to have your Spiritual Eyes ſo opened, as to behold your Teacher, which you have often heard, can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:105837:8"/> be removed into a Corner; for that is the good End of the Lord, in viſiting you who have had a large Day in this City; therefore, now that you may come to know the Work of Salvation, by a thorough Separation from all that which draws the Mind into Vanity from God, that thereby you may be the ſaved of the Lord, and of that num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber which may come to Mount <hi>SION</hi> with Songs of Deliverance, and enter into that Joy which all the faithful (who hide not their Talent in that Earthly Mind, which leads to a Carnal Liberty and Fleſhly Eaſe,) ſhall enter into; therefore, whilſt the Day of God's tender Viſitation, in the Riches of his long forbearing Love doth laſt, and whilſt he is yet ſtriving by his Spirit, harken and give Ear what the Spirit ſaith, which hath and doth ſay, <hi>Come, and all that will come may come;</hi> there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, what Excuſes will any make, who have had ſo much, or many Invitations of the Love of God? who hath alſo ſaid, <hi>My Spirit ſhall not always ſtrive with Man:</hi> Therefore, let none harden their Hearts, or ſtiffen their Necks againſt the Way of the Lord, which is as ſure this Day, as ever, as Righteous and Holy, as ever, and they that walk in it, muſt deny themſelves of all the contrary, as much as ever; and bleſſed be the Lord, this is not the Day in which the Lord will ſay to ſuch, <hi>My People pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh for want of Knowledge;</hi> therefore, let all take heed of the greater Condemnation: <hi>He that knows his Maſters Will, and doth it not, ſhall be beaten with many Stripes.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Dear Friends, In the tendering begetting Love of our God, is my Heart opened to you who are the Younger convinced amongſt us, for whom my
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:105837:8"/> Spirit, with many more, hath been, and is truly concerned with many Deſires to the Lord on your behalf, that as you have heard the Truth, and been Educated in the Truth, you may alſo receive the Truth in the Love of it, and come to be led and guided by it, into the Self denying Way of it, to take up the Croſs, and bear the Yoke in your Youth, that thereby you may come to wear the Crown of Faithfulneſs in your Riper Years: For it is the ſame this Day as ever. <hi>If you die not the Death of the Righteous, you cannot expect to be made Heirs of Everlaſting Life;</hi> therefore it behoves all to be concerned, and conſider what Spirit they are ſowing to; if to the Fleſh and carnal Deſires, of that you will certainly reap Corruption; but if to the Spirit, Life Everlaſting; <hi>for to be ſpiritually minded is Life and Peace:</hi> Bleſſed be the Lord, there are many Witneſſes of it, and now that there may be many more of thoſe who have heard it born Witneſs to; for the Lord hath cauſed many to riſe early, and go forth late to Preach the Ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laſting Goſpel amongſt you, which is glad Tydings of Peace to all that believe and obey the Goſpel; but to ſuch who do not obey, what Tidings doth it bring to your Houſes? O! Harken and again hear what the Spirit ſaith, you have been often directed to it, and it is the Inſpiration of the Holy Spirit of God muſt give you a right Under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding of theſe things that differ from it, what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever you may hear by thoſe who have had large Experience of the Way and Work of the Lord, which will be your great Condemnation if you walk not in it; but bleſſed be the Lord, there is a living Hope in that Faith which ſtands in
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:105837:9"/> the Power of God, that many will yet be awake<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned unto Righteouſneſs, and ſtirred up to walk in that bleſſed Way and Path of the Juſt, which is a ſhining Light, and will ſhine in them more and more, till the perfect Day; for the Sun of Righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teouſneſs is riſen, and his ſplendorous Beams are ſeen, yea, many have, and yet ſhall behold the Glory and Beauty that is in him, and be made Partakers of that healing Virtue which proceeds from him; therefore, all preſs forward through the Throng of all that which you find to oppoſe in your Hearts, that by Faith you may come to touch the Hem of his Garment, by which the Precious Vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue of his Life you may know conveyed to your im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mortal Souls. Dear Friends, the Lord is on his way, therefore be ye followers of him; why ſhould any ſtay behind, and miſs ſuch great Salvation as is offe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red in this our Day? Friends, be concerned and ſeek the Lord, that you may be found of him, and find find him to be your exceeding great Reward, for he is a rewarder of all them that diligently ſeek after him, and bleſſed be the Lord there is a Remnant that have ſought, but not in vain; yea, many faithful and living Teſtimonies have you heard of the ſame, there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore is my Heart ſtill in the Love of God drawn to remind you, that you come to be experimental Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſes; the Lord many of you know, and the Truth you know, therefore travel on and go forward in the Foot-ſteps of the Flock of God who are gone before, and many are entred into that Holy City, the Gates of which ſtand open to receive all who are truly poor in ſpirit, for they ſhall inherit the Kingdom of Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven,</p>
            <lg>
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:105837:9"/>
               <l>Which is a Place of great Felicity.</l>
               <l>Believe it you, and then come all and ſee,</l>
               <l>Where Joy and Comfort endleſs doth abound,</l>
               <l>To all unfeigned hearts whoſe Love is ſound;</l>
               <l>And travel on as <hi>Caleb, Joſhua</hi> did,</l>
               <l>Men of excellent Spirits, as you all may read.</l>
               <l>And this I alſo do you farther tell,</l>
               <l>There is great Happineſs in doing well.</l>
               <l>The benefit of which you'll ſurely find,</l>
               <l>If croſs you do all vain things in your mind;</l>
               <l>The Principle of Light and Truth is ſet</l>
               <l>In thy Heart, Man, and doth it often check.</l>
               <l>But this is a great Miſery in our day;</l>
               <l>Some hate Counſel, and thruſt Truths check away.</l>
               <l>But I deſire that none of you ſo do,</l>
               <l>To whom theſe following Lines do yet enſue.</l>
            </lg>
            <p>You who are the Children and Off-ſpring, yea, I may ſay, the natural Branches of ſuch who have been grafted into the true Vine; to many of you the Love of God ſtill reaches, that you may come to know a being grafted in alſo, and that you may receive Sap and Nouriſhment from the Root Chriſt Jeſus, that thereby you may come to grow freſh and green, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>membring the Willows by the Water-courſes, you having been often watered as with the Dew from Heaven, that now you may not be as fruitleſs Branch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>es, that the Lord may not have cauſe to cut off any natural Branch; but as you are Children, and Heirs of theſe Earthly things, which the Lord hath bleſſed many of your Parents with; that now you may not only therewith be content, but fervently deſire to be made Heirs, and Poſſeſſors of that heavenly Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure,
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:105837:10" rendition="simple:additions"/> and durable Riches which the Lord hath alſo enriched them with, that you may not be only Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren of the Fleſh, but come to know a being born of the Spirit, or that ſpiritual Birth brought forth in you, which is Heir of everlaſting Life; that when your Parents ſhall be called to leave theſe earthly Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bernacles, or Houſes of Clay, to poſſeſs an Houſe not made with hands but Eternal in the Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vens, which many are already called to then, as you come to poſſeſs and enjoy their Subſtance; here you may alſo be following them in that ſtraight and narrow way, which will lead and bring you to that ſame purchaſed Poſſeſſion, and everlaſting Inheritance when Time in this World ſhall be no more; that as the Lord hath been honoured, his Power magnified, and Truth exalted by many who have been as a kind of firſt Fruits, to the Praiſe of the Lord be it ſpoken, that now you who are as a following Generation, may be as a ſecond Spring on the ſame Ground, whoſe freſhneſs and greenneſs may ſo appear, as that you may be Inviters and En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>couragers of others to come and feed on the ſame Paſture; the Lord being your Shepherd, you may be able to ſay, <hi>we ſhall not want,</hi> having your Faith in him, and Hearts fixed upon him, that in all things your Eyes may be to him, and to the Honour of his great Name, which hath been as precious Ointment often poured forth amongſt you; the Savour of which hath cauſed many to love the Lord, and not only to love him, but an increaſe of Love to him hath been known, and this is that Love which thinks no Evil; the Lord ſtill increaſe it; this bears all things, endures and ſuffers all things; this Love alſo edifies and will build you up as an holy Houſe, as you ſee
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:105837:10"/> the Encreaſe of it; this is that Love which the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtle makes mention of, when he ſaid, <hi>All things are as Droſs and Dung in compariſon of the Riches of the Love of God, which hath been revealed and partaken of in this our Day, through Chriſt Jeſus our Lord:</hi> And now Dear Friends; my deſire to the Lord on your behalf, is, that you may have the Benefit of thoſe precious Promiſes; which are <hi>Yea,</hi> and <hi>Amen,</hi> unto the one Seed Chriſt Jeſus, which will be as you find him raiſing that Birth in you, which <hi>hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers and thirsts after Righteouſneſs:</hi> For ſuch the Lord hath, and will fill with the Treaſure of Wiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, and they ſhall know the Myſteries of his King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, and be fed with that Bread which comes down from Heaven; and here you will feed toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther as harmleſs Sheep of one Paſture, and be nou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhed up in that innocent Life in which the Plant will grow, that the Lord's Right hand hath planted; and here you will not only anſwer the good End of the Lord, but alſo the Care of your tender Parents; which hath not only been concerned for you their Children, but alſo for the Honour of God and the Glory of his Power, which I have often heard ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny publickly deſire, that this young Generation may come to witneſs the operating Virtue of it, to ſoften, tender, and mollifie their Heart; that by the effe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctual working thereof, they may know that Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trition of Spirit, which the Lord never did, nor will deſpiſe: Friends, ſlight not the Love of God, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe you have often and many frequent Tokens of it, but embrace it, and remember it is ſaid, <hi>Whilſt it's called to Day, harden not your Hearts, leſt a Night of Deprivation of theſe Mercies you now enjoy, ſhould approach any of you;</hi> Dear Friends, the Love
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:105837:11"/> of God enlarges my Heart to you, the which I de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire you may feel, to make room in you to receive; it will be your own Advantage, and a Cauſe of Joy and Comfort, to thoſe whom the Lord hath made inſtrumental in his hand, to the begetting of you to himſelf, and here you will be in a living Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacity, to glorifie God your Maker; and much might be ſaid for your Encouragement, but the Lord will not be wanting unto you, for his imme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diate Power will be preſent with you; as alſo ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Inſtruments in his hand, whom he hath, and may make helpful to you: And thus dear Friends, the God of all our Mercies will be honoured, the Knowledge of his Truth ſtill increaſed, and we to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether mutually comforted, which is the hearty Deſire of your Friend and Siſter,</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>ABIGAL FISHER.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:105837:11"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
